<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<project-overview>
  <name>TV Tantrum</name>
  <description>A gamified web platform that transforms children's media discovery into an engaging, intelligent experience. The application provides a secure, interactive interface for families to explore age-appropriate TV shows through advanced content recommendation and personalized user interactions.</description>
  
  <key-technologies>
    <technology>React with Tailwind CSS and shadcn/ui components</technology>
    <technology>Express.js backend with TypeScript</technology>
    <technology>PostgreSQL database with Drizzle ORM</technology>
    <technology>Real-time theme and metadata management</technology>
    <technology>Comprehensive content recommendation system</technology>
    <technology>Interactive user experience design</technology>
    <technology>Smart form components with validation</technology>
    <technology>TanStack Query for data fetching</technology>
  </key-technologies>

  <main-features>
    <feature>
      <name>TV Show Discovery & Browsing</name>
      <description>Advanced filtering system with age range, stimulation scores, themes, and interaction levels. Comprehensive search functionality with intelligent recommendations and alphabetically sorted theme filters.</description>
    </feature>
    
    <feature>
      <name>User Authentication & Profiles</name>
      <description>Secure user registration and login system with emoji badge progression (13 levels from "Tablet Baby 👶" to "Screen Sensei 🧘"), customizable profile backgrounds, and privacy-focused public profiles without email exposure.</description>
    </feature>
    
    <feature>
      <name>Content Rating & Reviews</name>
      <description>User-generated reviews with upvoting system, stimulation scoring, and community feedback mechanisms. Points awarded for engagement activities.</description>
    </feature>
    
    <feature>
      <name>Gamification System</name>
      <description>Points-based reward system with 13 emoji badge progression levels (25-2000 points), achievements for login streaks, reviews, upvotes, referrals, show submissions, and research reading. Leaderboard with clickable usernames for profile navigation.</description>
    </feature>
    
    <feature>
      <name>Admin Dashboard</name>
      <description>Comprehensive content management system with smart theme management, user administration, image optimization, and automated data synchronization. Features intelligent ThemeSelector component preventing duplicates and typos.</description>
    </feature>
    
    <feature>
      <name>Smart Theme Management</name>
      <description>Intelligent categorization system with autocomplete theme selector, duplicate prevention, automatic Title Case formatting, and synchronized storage across themes table, tv_show_themes junction table, and tv_shows array columns.</description>
    </feature>

    <feature>
      <name>Featured Content System</name>
      <description>Dynamic featured show highlighting with database flag support (is_featured column) and random carousel displays across six content categories on the home page.</description>
    </feature>
  </main-features>

  <recent-updates>
    <update date="2025-05-28">
      <title>Smart Theme Management System</title>
      <description>Implemented comprehensive ThemeSelector component with autocomplete, search functionality, duplicate prevention, and automatic Title Case formatting. Added themes API endpoint and integrated into both Add Show and Edit Show forms.</description>
    </update>
    
    <update date="2025-05-28">
      <title>Theme Database Synchronization</title>
      <description>Fixed critical synchronization issues between themes table and TV shows array columns. Standardized theme formatting (e.g., 'sing-a-long' → 'Sing Along', 'Super Hero themes' → 'Super Hero Themes') ensuring alphabetical sorting and consistent data across all storage locations.</description>
    </update>
    
    <update date="2025-05-28">
      <title>Enhanced Form Components</title>
      <description>Replaced manual theme input textareas with intelligent ThemeSelector components featuring visual badge management, existing theme detection, and seamless integration with current show data for editing workflows.</description>
    </update>

    <update date="2025-05-28">
      <title>User Profile & Badge System</title>
      <description>Implemented 13-level emoji badge progression system tied to point milestones, customizable profile background colors, privacy-focused public profiles, and clickable username navigation from leaderboard and admin dashboard.</description>
    </update>

    <update date="2025-05-28">
      <title>Featured Content & Home Page Enhancement</title>
      <description>Added is_featured column to shows table, implemented dynamic featured show highlighting, and created random carousel displays for six content categories on the home page for improved content discovery.</description>
    </update>
  </recent-updates>

  <database-schema>
    <table name="users">
      <description>User account information, authentication data, total_points for badge progression, and profile customization settings</description>
    </table>
    
    <table name="tv_shows">
      <description>Comprehensive TV show metadata including sensory details, themes array, platform availability, and is_featured flag for content highlighting</description>
    </table>
    
    <table name="themes">
      <description>Normalized theme data with proper Title Case formatting, alphabetical organization, and unique constraints to prevent duplicates</description>
    </table>
    
    <table name="tv_show_themes">
      <description>Junction table maintaining many-to-many relationships between shows and themes for data integrity and efficient querying</description>
    </table>
    
    <table name="reviews">
      <description>User-generated content reviews with ratings, upvote tracking, and community feedback mechanisms</description>
    </table>
    
    <table name="favorites">
      <description>User favorite shows tracking for personalized recommendations and points calculation</description>
    </table>
    
    <table name="research_summaries">
      <description>Educational content and research data for informed content selection and user points from reading activities</description>
    </table>

    <table name="review_upvotes">
      <description>Tracking system for review upvotes with user attribution and points calculation</description>
    </table>
  </database-schema>

  <api-endpoints>
    <endpoint path="/api/user" method="GET">
      <description>Retrieve current user information, authentication status, and badge progression data</description>
    </endpoint>
    
    <endpoint path="/api/tv-shows" method="GET">
      <description>Fetch TV shows with advanced filtering (themes, age range, stimulation score), search, pagination, and alphabetically sorted theme options</description>
    </endpoint>
    
    <endpoint path="/api/themes" method="GET">
      <description>Retrieve all available themes in alphabetical order for intelligent theme selection and autocomplete functionality</description>
    </endpoint>
    
    <endpoint path="/api/shows/:id" method="GET">
      <description>Get detailed information for a specific TV show including sensory data, themes, and related content</description>
    </endpoint>
    
    <endpoint path="/api/shows/:id" method="PATCH">
      <description>Update TV show information with smart theme synchronization across all database tables</description>
    </endpoint>
    
    <endpoint path="/api/reviews" method="POST">
      <description>Submit user reviews with ratings, content feedback, and automatic points allocation</description>
    </endpoint>
    
    <endpoint path="/api/favorites" method="POST/DELETE">
      <description>Manage user favorite shows for personalized experiences and points tracking</description>
    </endpoint>

    <endpoint path="/api/user/dashboard" method="GET">
      <description>Comprehensive user dashboard data including points breakdown, badge level, recent activity, and recommendations</description>
    </endpoint>

    <endpoint path="/api/users/:id/profile" method="GET">
      <description>Public user profile information with privacy protection (no email exposure) and badge display</description>
    </endpoint>
  </api-endpoints>

  <file-structure>
    <directory name="client/src">
      <file name="pages/home.tsx">Home page with featured content carousel and browsing interface</file>
      <file name="pages/browse.tsx">Advanced filtering with alphabetical theme sorting and search functionality</file>
      <file name="pages/detail.tsx">Detailed show information and user interactions</file>
      <file name="pages/admin-page.tsx">Administrative dashboard with smart theme management and user administration</file>
      <file name="pages/user-profile.tsx">Public user profiles with emoji badges and privacy protection</file>
      <file name="pages/user-dashboard.tsx">Personalized user dashboard with points and recommendations</file>
      <file name="components/ThemeSelector.tsx">Smart theme management component with autocomplete and duplicate prevention</file>
      <file name="components/ShowCard.tsx">Reusable TV show display component with theme badges</file>
      <file name="components/ShowFilters.tsx">Advanced filtering interface with alphabetical theme sorting</file>
      <file name="lib/badges.ts">Badge progression system with 13 emoji levels and point thresholds</file>
    </directory>
    
    <directory name="server">
      <file name="routes.ts">API endpoint definitions with theme management and user profile handling</file>
      <file name="database-storage.ts">Database operations with synchronized theme management across tables</file>
      <file name="index.ts">Server initialization and configuration</file>
    </directory>
    
    <directory name="shared">
      <file name="schema.ts">TypeScript type definitions and database schema with theme relationships</file>
    </directory>

    <directory name="utilities">
      <file name="sync-themes.js">Theme synchronization utility for maintaining data consistency</file>
      <file name="image-manager.js">Consolidated image management and optimization</file>
      <file name="data-manager.js">Consolidated data management and validation</file>
      <file name="api-data-updater.js">API integration for metadata updates</file>
    </directory>
  </file-structure>

  <key-accomplishments>
    <accomplishment>Smart theme management system preventing database inconsistencies and duplicates</accomplishment>
    <accomplishment>Intelligent form components with autocomplete, validation, and seamless editing workflows</accomplishment>
    <accomplishment>Robust filtering system with alphabetical sorting and multiple criteria support</accomplishment>
    <accomplishment>Scalable content management with comprehensive admin dashboard</accomplishment>
    <accomplishment>Engaging 13-level emoji badge progression system with point-based rewards</accomplishment>
    <accomplishment>Privacy-focused user profiles with customizable backgrounds and clickable navigation</accomplishment>
    <accomplishment>Synchronized data integrity across multiple theme storage locations</accomplishment>
    <accomplishment>Featured content system with dynamic highlighting and random carousels</accomplishment>
    <accomplishment>Comprehensive utility scripts for data management and synchronization</accomplishment>
    <accomplishment>Type-safe development with TypeScript and proper schema validation</accomplishment>
  </key-accomplishments>

  <current-status>
    <status>Fully functional smart theme management system deployed and tested</status>
    <status>All theme synchronization issues resolved with proper alphabetical sorting</status>
    <status>Both Add Show and Edit Show forms using intelligent ThemeSelector component</status>
    <status>Database consistency maintained across themes table, junction table, and show arrays</status>
    <status>User badge progression system operational with 13 emoji levels</status>
    <status>Featured content system ready for dynamic content highlighting</status>
    <status>Privacy-protected public profiles with clickable username navigation</status>
  </current-status>
</project-overview>